Hello, good evening, I’m from the city of
Здравствуйте Добрый вечер я из города
Khmelnitsk. You’re from Sevastopol, great
Хмельницке Вы откуда Севастополь пра а
country.
страна
What country is Sevastopol? City, country, I
Какая Севастополь Город страна какая я
don’t know
же не знаю
somewhere. But you don’t know. Well, okay, and
гдето А вы не знаете Ну ладно а
Khmelnitsky. This is where Khmelnitsky is in
Хмельницкий Это где Хмельницкий в
Ukraine. I live. What country do you
Украине Я живу А вы в какой стране
live in? I’m in Russia, it’s cool.  I
живёте я в России прикольно У меня
have a friend, she’s also in the city of
знакомая есть просто она тоже в городе
Sevastopol, but this one lives in Ukraine. Well,
Севастополе но в Украине живёт это-то Ну
let it be so, I understand, I understand, I just
пусть будет так понял понял то я просто
don’t know, he thinks, and so I’m
вот не знаю считает Да так вот я же и
asking, yes. Do you think I understand? I
спрашиваю да Как вы считаете понял Я же
already answered you. How long have you been living?  in
вам ответила уже А вы как давно живёте в
Russia in Russia
России в России
specifically Well, it turns out from the fourteenth
конкретно Ну получается с четырнадцатого
from the fourteenth year, yes, that is, as I
с четырнадцатого года да то есть я так
understand it, you lived, I was born in the Soviet
понимаю что вы жили родилась в Советском
Union. Well, that is, you lived in Ukraine
Союзе Ну бы То есть вы вы жили в Украине
and moved to Russia in 2005. I
а переехали в Россию так в м году В
mean, you moved Well, you lived, I was born
смысле переехала Ну вы жили я родилась
in general in the USSR yes yes then I got a
вообще в СССР да да потом получила
Ukrainian passport since it was Ukraine
паспорт Украины так как была Украина
so then there was a referendum so
так потом было референдум так
more statement Yes more statement Yes and
боле изявление Да бо боле изявление Да и
what next Yes and what happened to yours I
что дальше Да и что случилось с вашим
got a Russian passport that’s all that
пас получила паспорт России вот и всё
you
ство что вы
did nothing That is, you  I still have my
сделали ничего То есть у вас остался
passport and citizenship, yes Well, it’s lying there, and I
паспорт и гражданство да Ну лежит а я
love these Lezhinos. Why do you need to lie there, why are
люблю этих Лежино А зачем вам лежать
you holding a Ukrainian
зачем вы держите украинский
passport, why
паспорт зачем
throw away the question, why do I have it, I have
выбрасывать вопрос зачем его у меня
documents, look, my relative
документы смотрите моего родственника
is not alive, his
нет в живых его
document,
документ
you’re an idiot, young man, not me, for some
Вы идиот молодой человек не я просто
reason I just meet all the Crimeans  everyone is so
почему-то всех крымчан встречаю все
happy, but everything is forbidden in
такие довольные но все де запрещено в
the sense of holding it, it’s lying with me, they’re
смысле держит он лежит у меня лежат
related to me, I have the documents of a
родстве у меня лежат документы
relative of the deceased just lying there, I
родственника умершего просто лежит я не
can’t throw it away, as if you can’t, they tore it up and
могу выкинуть как не можете порвали и
threw it away in Ukrainian, why and why why throw away
выкинули украинский зачем а зачем зачем
the documents, they’re just lying abroad, they’re lying, imagine,
выбрасывать документы просто лежат у
imagine  The passport
представляете Паспорт
will expire, it will still be
просрочится он будет лежать всё
there, citizenship is not expired,
ра гражданство Гражданство не просра
citizenship is not expired, no no, that is,
воет гражданство так не прос нет нет то
look, it just turns out that
есть смотрите просто получается что
you are coming to Turkey to relax.
смотрите вы приезжаете в Турцию отдыхать
Yes, and you can be deported there as a citizen of Ukraine
Да и вас там могут как гражданку Украины
to Ukraine, I
и депортировать в Украину я правильно
understand correctly why suddenly because  you are in
понимаю с чего вдруг потому что вы во
all the databases of Ukraine I have no idea Yes, well,
всех базах Украины Я понятия не имею Да
that is, you
ну то есть вы во всех базах Украины
are listed as a Ukrainian citizen in all the databases of Ukraine Yes, you
числите украинской гражданкой Да вы не
have not lost your citizenship, yes, that is, for example,
вышли из гражданства да то есть например
you are in Turkey. So I am now
вы в Турцию Так вот я сейчас вас
registering you and then transferring you to
записываю да передаю потом в
certain services. Yes, they are adding you to  base
определённые службы Да вас вносят в базу
and, for example, at the airport then in Istanbul
и например в аэропорту потом Стамбула
Interpol like they arrest you and as a
Интерпол типа вас арестовывают да как
collaborator
коллаборант
Well, these are your wet fantasy Re
Ну это твои влажные фантази вные Ре
really wet pres I can imagine what
реально влажные пре Я представляю Какие
you will be like when dual citizenship is prohibited in Ukraine,
вы будете когда это в Украине запрещено
this is firstly and
двойное гражданство это во-первых
secondly if my state
во-вторых если бы моё государство
would say to surrender  I would have
сказало бы сдать паспорт я бы его
handed over my passport, and I understood everything about it, I understood, that is,
сдала вот и всё про жи понял понял то
look, it turns out that
есть смотрите получается что у вас даже
you didn’t even give it to Russia somewhere,
вы даже не отдали в Россию где-то вот
some people told me when I received
мне некоторые говорили я когда получал
Russian citizenship, I handed over this
российское гражданство Я отдал этот
Ukrainian passport, they gave it back, well, no, it was
украинский паспорт отдали есть ну нет
n’t there  so
там нет было так
those liable for military service were obliged to surrender But
военнообязанные были обязаны сдать А вот
look well, why would you even
Хорошо смотри для чего вам вообще может
need a civilian one? For what I’ve
понадобится гражданским ни Для чего мне
never got it, I don’t just have the documents lying around
ни разу не пона мне ещё не просто лежит
well,
хорошо
I
документы меня
was baptized in Ukraine No, not What does a
крестили при Украине Нет не Причём тут
baptismal passport have to do with it if you if you were
паспорт крещения если вам если Вам
paid if you were paid if  They would
заплатили если Вам заплатили если Вам
pay you 100 dollars, you would tear up
заплатили 100 долларов вы бы порвали
your Ukrainian
свой украинский
passport. Why do I need money? Why would you
паспорт А зачем мне бабки А за 1.000
tear up your Ukrainian
долларов порвали бы украинский свой
passport for 1,000 dollars? Well, you just have it lying around
паспорт зачем Ну у вас он просто лежит
some piece of paper. Well, this is an idiotic,
какая-то бумажка Ну это идиотский у вас
idiotic question, that is, a Ukrainian
идиотский вопрос о то есть украинский
passport is more expensive to you than 1000  dollars, for some reason, a
паспорт вам дороже чем 1000 долларов
Ukrainian passport is
приу украинский паспорт вам почему-то
more expensive to you than 1,000 dollars. This is good, I
дороже чем 1.000 долларов Это хорошо я
see that Crimeans value Ukrainian
вижу крымчане хорошо ценят украинские
passports well, but let’s say that for 10,000
паспорта а давайте так за 10.000
dollars you would tear up yours and burn your
долларов вы бы порвали свой и сожгли
Ukrainian
украинский
passport, why would I tear up and burn it, ok, ok,
паспорт зачем я буду рвать жечь капец
ok, look, for 10,000
капец су капец хорошо смотрите за 10.000
dollars, you  they would tear up the piece of paper that
долларов вы бы порвали бумажку которая
you have for a
лежит у вас на
century No, you wouldn’t mean it if you I if
столет Нет вы бы не про если вам я если
someone offered me money for something
бы мне кто-то за что-то предложил бы
I wouldn’t do it on principle, it
деньги Я бы принципиально это не делала
doesn’t matter if it was the EU I’m right away,
неважно что бы это было ЕС я сразу гожу
look if they tell me 10,000  dollars
смотри если мне говорят 10.000 долларов
so that you tear up just this piece of paper
чтобы ты порвал вот просто бумажку вот
that is fundamentally fundamentally
эту которая жи принципиально
fundamentally I wouldn’t
принципиально принципиально Я бы это не
do it Yeah that’s fundamentally understood interestingly
делала Ага вот така принципиально понял
well, can you imagine
интересно хорошо а представляете
for example Putin Putin addresses you from the
например Путин Путин обращается к вам с
TV and says there
телевизора и говорит там
What’s your name
Как вас зовут
by the way doesn’t matter Yes March it doesn’t matter vna Yes
кстати неважно Да марта неважно вна Да
do it  for me, the President of the Russian
сделайте для меня президента Российской
Federation Tear up the Ukrainian passport, you would have torn
Федерации Порви украинский паспорт вы бы
it up for the sake of Putin, I would have just
прорвали ради Путина я бы его просто
taken it and handed it over, that’s all. Why didn’t they tear it up? Why
отнесла сдала бы вот и всё А почему не
tear it up? Well, who
порвали Зачем рвать Ну кто
really do you have? Maybe
как действительно У вас есть Может это
you’re
вы вы
thinking about it, or maybe you’re not inventing something there
думаете а может вы там что-то выдумывает
Show me just the cover, don’t open the
не Покажите просто обложку не открывайте
surname, but show the cover that there is a
э фамилию а покажите обложку что есть
Russian passport. I would also like to show you the surname, I do
нский паспорт Я бы вам ещё фамилию
n’t care, I’m interested in it, you have it
показы не мне мне интересно он у вас
in the
типа в
cover where,
обложечный
well, where are the old documents Labor,
где ну где там старые документы Трудовая
where is the old one, somewhere is the truth
где старая где где-то лежит лежит правда
and you know in the bag  and when was the
и вы знаете пакетике а когда вы его
last time you looked at it? Of course I know where all
последний раз смот Конечно знаю где все
the documents are. When was the last time you
документы Когда вы последний раз
looked at your Ukrainian passport, when
смотрели свой украинский паспорт когда
oh, I don’t remember. To be honest, well, that’s about what to
ой не помню Если честно Ну примерно что
look at. Well, we were going through these
на него смотреть Ну вот перебирали эти
documents. When was the last time you saw him,
документы Когда вы его видели последний
listen? I can’t say when I
раз слушайте Не могу сказать когда
looked at the church one.  my book Well, this
смотрела церковную свою книж Ну в этом
year somewhere
году где-то
Yes, no, in the past,
Да нет в прошлого
listen, mine is lying there, my
слушайте лежит мой мои паспорта
expired, not expired, passports are in
просроченные не просроченные лежат в
bags there Well, everything expired is
пакетики там Ну и просроченное всё
just lying there, the documents of my deceased
просто лежит документы моего умершего
relative are also lying there, they were thrown out for me too.
родственника тоже там лежат мне их тоже
Well, why look, why do you need
выбросили Ну зачем смотри зачем вам мого
advice from a relative  Soviet Ukrainians
совет родственника советские украинские
are lying there,
лежат
Ukraine pas, he means something to you Yes, he
че Украин пас он что-то для вас
just doesn’t mean anything
значит Да ничего просто ничего не значит
That is, he’s just
То есть он просто
a piece of paper Well, yes, a useless piece of paper Well, yes,
бумажка Ну да бесполезная бумажка Ну да
the same as any piece of paper that you
такая же как и любая бумажка кото
used, that is, look at the Ukrainian
пользовалась то есть смотри украинский
passport that you have, it’s just as
паспорт который у вас лежит такая же
useless  the piece of paper is like other
бесполезная бумажка как и другие
useless pieces of paper, there are some
бесполезные бумажки там какие-то
pieces of paper there, yes, it’s there, and that’s all. Why do
листочки да да лежит да и всё А почему
you throw away other pieces of paper? I have a piece of paper lying around, oh,
другие бумажки вы выкидывает У меня есть
how did it
лежит бумажка э как она правильно я
apply correctly for a passport? There’s a criminal record, there’s also a piece of paper,
подавала на паспорт судимость лежит тоже
I didn’t throw it away. Why do
бумажка я её не выбросила Да почему
you throw away some pieces of paper?  Yes, but
некоторые бумажки вы кидаете Да а
you didn’t throw away the Ukrainian pieces of paper.
украинские бумажки вы не
I mean, this is such a
выкинули В смысле А это такая за
nail-biter, it’s Ukrainian. I
гвоздово именно украински у меня все
have all the pieces of paper lying around, I even have the receipts from
бумажки лежат у меня даже чеки лежат
when I was being treated. It’s not the Chekish I
когда я лечилась есть не это чекиш в
studied in. It’s necessary. Yes, it’s necessary, and then it’s
училась это надо Да это нужно и тут
clear why, so they probably need to be
понятно что же так наверное их надо
burned  there is no way to burn them, you can also
спалить там сжечь нет их можно тоже
document There
документ Там
is a ko no matter
есть ко никакой
how special it is ko chi kaka
кой э как бы особой оно значимости ко чи
there I have a lot of things which year you
кака там у меня много чего кам году вы
chi checks you have from what year the difference I’m
чи чеки у вас с какого года разница Мне
just wondering how much money they
просто интересно как на сколько денег
treated you for and I didn’t cure you  I’m collecting,
вас лечили и не вылечили я собираю
understand this, I’m collecting all the pieces of paper in
поймите так я собираю все бумажки за всю
my entire life. They’re lying around. That is, you’re
свою жизнь Они у меня лежат То есть вы
just trash, everyone’s pieces of paper are trash. There are
просто мусор весь всем бумажки мусорные
notebooks from school, you
Там тетрадки из школы
’re collecting treatment, everything that’s important, receipts.
собираете лечение всё что важно чеки А
Can you show me the storage of your
можете показать склад своих
pieces of paper? I won’t go into the room, but
бумажек я не буду идти в комнату но у
I have it there  Daddy, as I understand it, no So
меня там папочка я так понимаю нет Так
wait Daddy If you
подождите Папочка Если вы ска все
collect all the papers you have there, in short, damn, the
бумажки собираете у вас там короче блин
floor of the apartment should be used Yes no Why are
пол квартиры должно быть бу Да нет Зачем
you in pain And how sick are you? I
вы боль А на сколько вы больны У меня
have Daddy
есть Папочка
files How
файли Насколько Вы
sick are you physically morally
больны физически морально
morally morally I don’t have those  there are
морально морально Нет у меня таких
no papers, that is, I have
бумажек нет то есть ещё не
n’t applied yet, there were no problems in
доос не обращалась не было проблем в
this
этой
with
с
eating morally, not eating, yes, and
есть морально е не есть есть да вот а
here you are It seems you’re getting out of it again Yes, help me out
вам там Кажется Вы опять выкручивается
like that I’m just I’m just you
Да выручи так Я просто я просто вы мне
just lifted my spirits today
просто сегодня подняли настроение Вам
Thank you so much I love meeting you so much
огромнейшее спасибо Я так люблю
Crimeans who hold an expensive
встречать крымчан которые держат дорогой
Ukrainian passport Yes,
для себя украинский паспорт Да потому
because they are waiting without twisting, without twisting, I’m not
что ждут не выкручивая не выкручивая не
waiting, I’m not waiting, without twisting, I’m not waiting, I’m not waiting, without
жду не жду не выкручивая не жду не жду
twisting, I don’t need to be told, I’m waiting for
не выкручивая не надо говорить меня
nothing in the situation. The Armed Forces of
ничего жду во ситуаци Вооружённые силы
Ukraine are entering Sevastopol just like they
Украины заходят в Севастополь так же как
entered the
зашли в
[ __ ] No you  what will you do with your
херн Нет ты за будет делать со своим
Ukrainian
украинским
passport, you will come out and show it, but I
паспортом вы выйдете и покажете а у меня
have an expired Ukrainian passport, I
есть просроченный украинский паспорт я
kept it, I didn’t
его держала я его не
burn it Oh, this is probably your favorite,
сжигала Ой вот это любимое наверное ваше
this is your favorite, to spin with this passport Well,
это твоё любимое с этим паспортом
yes, here in Kheson No, you
крутить Ну да вот в хесоне Нет ты
Neli wrote the referendum was there
Нели написали референдум был там чуть ли
almost 100% supported how the Russians ran away
не 100% поддержали как русские убежали
so everything was fine, everyone turned out to have
так всё нормально всех оказались
passports and that’s it. Probably expected this.
паспорта и всё Наверное это ожидал
Probably
Наверно это
expected this. I’ll take out my passport and show you and I’ll
ожидал я вытащу паспорт покажу и буду
tear up in front of you that you provoked me with this. I’m
при тебе рвать что ты меня вот это вот
interested. I’m
спровоцировал мне интересно Вот мне
wondering when the Ukrainian troops
интересно когда вот воны си Украины
will come in  in Sevastopol you will throw a
зайдут в Севастополь вы вы кинете
Russian passport you will leave Crimea Or you will
русский паспорт уедете из Крыма Или вы
just get a Ukrainian one No I’m
просто достанете украински Нет я никуда
not going anywhere yes Well you will benefit from the Ukrainian
не уеду да Ну вы будете польз украинским
passport so no I will be Russian good But
пасм так нет буду российским хорошо А
if you look if it won’t be any other way
если вот смотрите если по-другому уже не
Well wait Crimea will no longer be
будет Ну подождите Крым буде уже не
there  it won’t be different, neither will it be because it wo
будет не будет подругому нен тоже потому
n’t be Why won’t it be why
не будет Почему не буде почему вот
imagine that it won’t Crimea won’t be
Представьте что будет не Крым не будет
Well why than the same thing According to the
Ну почему чем так же самое По
Constitution Well why won’t it be Well
Конституции Ну почему не будет Ну а
why so sure look confident I
почему так уверен смотрите уверено Мне
was scared then now no it won’t be
было страшно тогда сейчас нет не будет
then I
тогда мне
was
было
git, I won’t be on my mind Crimea is like they
гите я не буду н уме Крым типа де
occupied, here come the troops you
оккупировали вот приходят войска вы вы
will What will you do with the Russian
будете Что вы будете делать с российским
passport and the
паспортом и с
Ukrainian one I will then tear up the Ukrainian ones
украинским я тогда порву украинские
then And when they come everything is super we are waiting for
тогда А когда придут всё супер ждём
Ukra to see you Well hey damn I so adore the
Укра до встречи Ну эй бли я так обожнюю
tsx of all the nuclear Crimeans  for Russia for
цх всех ядерных крымчан за Россию за
Russia Yes, well, I’m trying to get a Ukrainian passport, I
Росси Да ну паспорт Я тримаю украинский
don’t need a wine, I don’t need it, I just want to
он не нужен вин мене не потреба ж просто
trample on it absolutely Well, I’m going to get it, I’m going to get a
якийсь попирать абсолютно Ну я её тримаю
Ukrainian passport, are you sure
Я тримаю украинский паспорт Вы что не
you won’t be like that? Are you sure you won’t leave Crimea forever Forever Forever
такого не буде Ты что не окпу всё Крым
Forever
же назавжди Навсегда Навсегда Навсегда
Russia is here forever  but in Ukrainian I
Россия здесь навсегда но по украинский я
[music]
[музыка]
[laughter]
[смех]
try to
тримаю
check the letter on my Telegram directly at the same time axis
чекайте пись на мий Telegram прям зараз
VN
ось ВН
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube taking
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the scum of ORV in your ban and even
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
more videos I don’t show people sometimes I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for that
показуе информация про стримы тому для
In addition, we need to write an operational link
того щоб мы оперативный звязок пишиться
right away and in the meantime, in telegra okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм
video, also tezh Tsikava and Korisna information
видео ще теж цикава и корисна информация
and we are sorry for you, trimati postiyny
и ми повинни з вами тримати постийний
operational link,
оперативний звязок
in addition, show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
letter
пись